Saratoga Springs Open Space Project; Records apap155
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Programs and Issues, 1970-1972; 1981-1986; 1989-2002; 3; 4.36 cubic ft.
  - "Bypassing the City"Capital District Business Review, 1996 November 11-1996 November 17 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 16)
  - "Artists Paint The Undiscovered Park"Saratogian, 1996 July 15 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 17)
  - "Apartment Complex concerns State Park"Saratogian, 1996 November 8 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 18)
  - "The 'Art' of Controversy"Albany Times Union, 1996 August 27 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 19)
  - "Sate gets no Bids on Spa State Park Golf Course Proposal"Daily Gazette, 1996 September 17 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 20)
  - "Membership of Truck Bypass Task Force not Balanced"Saratogian, 1996 August 2 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 21)
  - "Spa Park Course Contract to Last 35 Years"Saratogian, 1996 August 8 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 22)
  - "New Parks Group Members Look to Maintain Access to Outdoors"Saratogian, 1996 August 5 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 23)
  - "Park to Spend $1M on Peerless Pool Upgrade"Saratogian, 1996 July 30 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 24)
  - "Spa Park is Serving Enough Traffic Needs", Roy Rotheim Saratogian, 1996 July 21 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 25)
  - "Park to Spend $1 million on Peerless Pool Upgrade"Saratogian, 1996 July (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 26)
  - "Local Residents to Join Parks Commission"Saratogian, 1996 July 20 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 27)
  - "Truck Route Through State Park Unrealistic"Saratogian, 1996 July 20 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 28)
  - "O'Connell says Park, Bypass can Coexist"Saratogian, 1996 July 16 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 29)
  - "Secret Garden or Dump"Saratogian, 1996 July 12 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 30)
  - "Readers React to NYT Bypass Editorial"Saratogian, 1996 July 11 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 31)
  - "Park Belongs to the People"Saratogian, 1996 July 11 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 32)
  - "Mayor Short-Sighted"Saratogian, 1996 July 11 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 33)
  - "Truck Pollution Worst than NYC"Saratogian, 1996 July 11 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 34)
  - "Park Bypass not a Local Decision"Saratogian, 1996 July 11 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 35)
  - "Mayor: Opinion Unwelcome on Bypass"Saratogian, 1996 July 4 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 36)
  - "Keep Trucks out of Saratoga Park", NY Times, 1996 June 29 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 37)
  - "$500,000 Found for Bypass Study"Daily Gazette, 1996 June 14 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 38)
  - "Someday, They'll Soar., Picture of Herons by Ed Burke"The Saratogian, 1996 June 29 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 39)
  - "Castro: Cautions Commercial use can Help Fund State Parks System"Saratogian, 1996 June 5 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 40)
  - "Mayor Still Pushing Bypass for Spa State Park"Daily Gazette, 1996 May 4 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 41)
  - "City Council Oks Truck Bypass Proposal"Saratogian, 1996 May 8 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 42)
  - "City Council Votes Tonight on Bypass"Saratogian, 1996 May 7 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 43)
  - "O'Connell Unable to Sway Castro", Gazette, 1996 May 3 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 44)
  - Elephant Talk Republican News Letter, 1996 Spring (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 45)
  - Speaking Out: Doug Ward "Courts Likely Will Strike Down Park Bypass Proposal"Saratogian, 1996 May 7 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 46)
  - "Don't Take Away Park Peace"Saratogian, 1996 May 7 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 47)
  - "Bypass Would Endanger Students"Saratogian, 1996 May 7 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 48)
  - Editorial: "City Council Should Vote for Bypass Through State Park"Saratogian, 1996 May 7 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 49)
  - "Raceway, Polo Group May Bid for Spa Golf Course"Daily Gazette, 1996 May 3 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 50)
  - "Saratoga Endorses Truck Bypass"Daily Gazette, 1996 May 2 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 51)
  - "Golf Course Firms Flock to Saratoga"Daily Gazette, 1996 April 27 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 52)
  - "Realistic Plan Needed for Bypass"Saratogian, 1996 April 25 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 53)
  - "Find Reasonable Alternative to Truck Route Through State Park", Letter to Editor Saratogian, 1996 April 22 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 54)
  - "Truck Route is Debated"Daily Gazette, 1996 April 17 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 55)
  - "Critics Urge Council to Pass on Park Bypass"Saratogian, 1996 April 17 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 56)
  - "City GOP Criticized for Backing Park Route"Saratogian, 1996 April 16 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 57)
  - "City GOP Backs Park Bypass"Saratogian, 1996 April 13 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 58)
  - "Mayor Pushes Bypass"Daily Gazette, 1996 April 13 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 59)
  - "Unite Behind Park Bypass"Saratogian, 1996 April 12 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 60)
  - "Park a Sanctuary for Wildlife", Dave Gibson, Letter to Editor Saratogian, 1996 April 9 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 61)
  - "Of Jobs and Frogs"Capital District Business Review, 1996 April 1-1996 April 7 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 62)
  - "Truck Route Would Destroy Unspoiled Beauty of Park"Saratogian, 1996 April 1 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 63)
  - "Washington Street Very Dangerous because of Traffic"Saratogian, 1996 March 30 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 64)
  - "Herons add to Debate"Daily Gazette, 1996 March 29 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 65)
  - "A Walk in the Park"Saratogian, 1996 March 29 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 66)
  - "Financing of Park Bypass Still Major Issue"Saratogian, 1996 March 28 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 67)
  - "Bypass Task Force Recommends Route Through Park"Saratogian, 1996 March 27 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 68)
  - "Saratoga Urged to Push for Park Truck Route"Daily Gazette, 1996 March 27 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 69)
  - "Panel Backs Truck Route Through Park"Albany Times Union, 1996 March 27 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 70)
  - "Spa to Seek Services from Non-Profits"Daily Gazette, 1996 March 25 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 71)
  - "Spa Park Chief on Right Road"Daily Gazette, 1996 March 25 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 72)
  - "Pataki's Environmental Record Dismal, Groups Say"Daily Gazette, 1996 March 22 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 73)
  - "Residents Split on Bypass Opposition"Saratogian, 1996 March 22 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 74)
  - "Assemblymen Say State Takes Low Road in Highway Projects"Albany Times Union, 1996 March 22 (Box 4 (3-Programs and Issues), Folder 75)
  - Vote Yes! Organization, Mounted Sign, 2002 (Flat-file 1)
  - 15th Anniversary, Poster, 2002 (Flat-file 2)
  - "Undiscovered Park" Art Exhibit, Signs, 1996 (Flat-file 3)
  - Vote Yes! Organization, Signs, 2002 (Flat-file 4)
  - Ephemera, 3.545
    - Water Bottle with Bicycle System Map, Undated (Box 1 (3-Programs and Issues))
    - Open Space Project, Button, Undated (Box 1 (3-Programs and Issues))
    - Open Space Project, Donation Can, Undated (Box 1 (3-Programs and Issues))
    - Open Space Project, Tote Bag, Undated (Box 1 (3-Programs and Issues))
- Trails, 1986-2000; Undated; 4; 1.33 cubic ft.
  The OSP is responsible for planning, organizing and frequently funding the construction of a number of trails in and around Saratoga Springs. These include nature trails like the Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, river trails like the Kayaderosseras Creek Canoe and Kayak Trail, and more urban trails such as the Bikeway recreational trail system. The materials in this series consist of maps, articles, correspondence, reports, and news clippings relating to the various trail building projects. Also represented are various OSP celebrations of National Trail Day. Extensive news clipping files are filed separately at the end of the series.
  - Benefits of Trails, Report, Articles, 1993; 1995-1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 1)
  - Bike Stanchions, 1995-1996; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 2)
  - Biking Information, Newsletters, Leaflets, Correspondence, 1993-1994; 1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 3)
  - Biking Ordinances, 1986; 1994 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 4)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Correspondence, Notes, Diagrams, 1993; 1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 5)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Educator's Guide, Correspondence, 2000 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 6)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Hunting Regulations, 1987-1988; 1993-1995; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 7)
  - Bog Meadow Creek Nature Trail, Fliers, Publications, Photographs, 1994-1995; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 8)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Installation of Signs, 2001 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 9)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Make a Difference Day, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 10)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Maps, Diagrams, 1993; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 11)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, News Clippings, 1992-2000 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 12)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Opening Celebration, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 13)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Original Railway, Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 14)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Proposed Extension, Proposal, News Clippings, Map, 1995-1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 15)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Request for Extension, Correspondence, Diagrams, 1995 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 16)
  - Bog Meadow Brook Nature Trail, Trail Work Days, Sign-Up Sheets, 1993; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 17)
  - Champlain Canal Ride, 1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 18)
  - Community Trails, Articles, 1986; 1992; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 19)
  - Cops on Bikes Program, News Clippings, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 20)
  - Glen Mitchell Nature Trail, Educational Material, Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 21)
  - "How You Can Get Involved in the Heritage Trails Project", Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 22)
    Fact Sheet, News Clippings.
  - Jenilu Schoolman, 1987; 1996; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 23)
  - Kayaderosseras Creek, Trail Clearing by Andrew Knutson, 2000 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 24)
  - Mohawk-Hudson Bicycle Route, Maps, Pamphlet, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 25)
  - Mohawk Valley Trail, Report, News Clippings, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 26)
  - National Trails Day, Invitation List, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 27)
  - National Trails Day, Proclamation, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 28)
  - National Trails Day, Thank You Letters, Correspondence, Mailing List, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 29)
  - National Trails Day Update, Newsletter, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 30)
  - Nature Conservancy, Wilton Proposal, Report, Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 31)
  - New York State Trails Plan, 1993; 1995; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 32)
  - North Woods Mountain Bike Issue, Notes, Draft Proclamation, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 33)
  - "Public Relations: Promoting Your Trail Event of Trail System", Lin Lindert, Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 34)
  - Recreational Trail System, Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 35)
  - Recreational Trail System, Custom Water Bottles, Correspondence, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 36)
  - Recreational Trail System, Field Reconnaissance Notes, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 37)
  - Recreational Trail System, Maps, 1990-1992; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 38)
  - Recreational Trail System, Opening Celebration, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 39)
  - Recreational Trail System, Opening Celebration, Bike Safety Rodeo, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 40)
  - Recreational Trail System, Opening Celebration, Parade, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 41)
  - Recreational Trail System, "Planning and Design Services for the East Side Bikeway Loop", Saratoga Associates, 1991 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 42)
  - Recreational Trail System, Planning Board, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 43)
  - Recreational Trail System, Press Release, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 44)
  - Recreational Trail System, Proposal Segments, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 45)
  - Recreational Trail System, The Saratoga Associates, Proposal, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 46)
  - Recreational Trail System, Signage Proposal, Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 47)
  - Recreational Trail System, Study, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 48)
  - Recreational Trail System, Study, Executive Summary, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 49)
  - Saratoga Bicycle Trail, Tree Planting Specification, 1995 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 50)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee Articles, Publications, 1986; 1992-1993; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 51)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, American Greenway DuPont Awards, Application, Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 52)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, Biking Pamphlets, Biking Trail Maps, 1992; 1996; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 53)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 54)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, Grant Applications, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 55)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, Hunting and Warning Signs, 1995; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 56)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, Interpretive Signs, Articles, Notes, 1993-1994; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 57)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, Maps, Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 58)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, Meeting Agendas, Minutes, 1993 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 59)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, Meeting Minutes, Notes, Memoranda, Newsletter, 1995-1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 60)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, Meeting Minutes, Notes, Correspondence, 1997 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 61)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Services, National Park Service Rivers, Trails and Conservation Assistance, 1992-1993; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 62)
  - Saratoga County Heritage Trail Committee, National Park Service Rivers, Trails and Conservation Assistance, Letters of Support, 1992; 1994 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 63)
  - Soroptimists, Notes, Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 64)
  - Trail, News Clippings, 1996-1999 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 65)
  - Trail Cleaning, News Clippings, 2000 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 66)
  - Trail Guides, Pamphlets, Newsletters, 1994-1996; 1998; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 67)
  - Trails Liability, Articles, Memoranda, 1992; 1994; 1997 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 68)
  - Tree Planting, Leaflets, News Clippings, 1995; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 69)
  - Water Day, Fliers, Leaflets, 1995 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 70)
  - Walkable and Bikeable Communities Conference, Conference Materials, Correspondence, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 71)
  - Walkable and Bikeable Communities Conference, Mailing Lists, 1996; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 72)
  - Walkable and Bikeable Communities Conference, Registration Forms, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 73)
  - Wildflower Planting, Correspondence, Fliers, Notes, 1997; Undated (Box 1 (4-Trails), Folder 74)
  - "Board Gives up on Wooded Trail, Loses Grant"Daily Gazette, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 1)
  - "Malta Seeks State grant to build Bike Trail"Daily Gazette, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 2)
  - "Railroad Run"Daily Gazette, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 3)
  - "Use Trials to Promote Health Rails to Trails", Press Piece, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 4)
  - "Coast to Coast Rec. Trail"The Saratogian, 1998 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 5)
  - "Recreation Trail on Drawing Board"Daily Gazette, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 6)
  - "P.R.-Wetlands:Artist Respond", Press Release, 1994 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 7)
  - "Ballston Plans to Extends Bike Park"Daily Gazette, Undated (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 8)
  - Bicycling in NY, Newspaper Clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 9)
  - "Clifton Park Eyes New Route for Bike Trail"Daily Gazette, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 10)
  - "Spa County Again Seeks $1 million For Bike Trail"Daily Gazette, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 11)
  - "Volunteers Get Path Ready For Winter"The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 12)
  - "Woman Attacked On Bike Path"The Saratogian, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 13)
  - "Photo of bike trial sign"The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 14)
  - "Beat Cops To Hop On Bikes"The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 15)
  - "39 mile Spa City Bike Trail Opens With Floral Fanfare", The Post Star, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 16)
  - "Saratoga Springs Bike Path Opens Saturday"The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 17)
  - "Local Events Abound on National Trails Day", Poor Richard's Saratoga Journal, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 18)
  - "Bike Patrols Begin"The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 19)
  - "New Bike Trial Wonderful, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 20)
  - "New Bikeway System takes Saratogian Cyclist For A Ride", The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 21)
  - "Bicyclist Celebrate Opening of Saratoga Trail System", The Sunday Gazette, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 22)
  - "Bike Path Leads City Along Recreation Route"The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 23)
  - "Parade Will Put Petals to the Pedal"Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 24)
  - "Take a Hike, Ride a Bike on National Trial Day", The Sunday Gazette, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 25)
  - "Saratoga Readies New Bike Trail"Daily Gazette, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 26)
  - "Join local celebration of National Trial Day"Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 27)
  - "Agreement Reached on Road Safety"Albany Times Union, 1993 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 28)
  - "Hike Bike Trial gets Ok"The Saratogian, 1993 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 29)
  - "Make a Difference Day", 1993 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 30)
  - "Public Hearing Set on Bike Trail Proposal"Post Star, 1993 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 31)
  - "Recreation Trails needed in Spa City"The Saratogian-Editorial page, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 32)
  - Bike Trial, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 33)
  - "Clearing way for Recreational Trials', Gazette reporter, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 34)
  - "Bike on, Malta!" Community News, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 35)
  - "The Open Space Project", Lisa Massaroni, Poor Richard's Saratoga Journal, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 36)
  - "Feds could Fund Bike/Bike trial"The Saratogian, Undated (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 37)
  - "Cyclist Fight for Right of Way"The Saratogian, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 38)
  - "Bike Path For City On A Roll"The Saratogian, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 39)
  - "Panel Backs 41 Mile Pathway"Albany Times Union, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 40)
  - "City Bike and Hike Trial Likely To Win Approval"The Saratogian, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 41)
  - "City Should Support Hiking, Biking Trails", 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 42)
  - "Panel Reveals Bike Path Plan", Gazette reporter, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 43)
  - "Hitting the Trail, By Foot or Pedal", Times Union, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 44)
  - "City Open Space Committee shape proposed bike route"The Saratogian, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 45)
  - "Committee Expands Plan for City Recreation Trails", 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 46)
  - "Open Space group to release Plans for Recreation Trial", 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 47)
  - "Recreation Trials could someday line map", The Sunday Gazette, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 48)
  - "Vermont Bike paths to stretch out", Burlington Free Press, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 49)
  - "From Boston to the Beltway-Bike path", Undated (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 50)
  - Bikeabout, 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 51)
  - "Group plans public session on recreation trail", 1992 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 52)
  - "Cyclist ask for State Representation", USA Today, 1991 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 53)
  - "Spa City bike path gets rolling with $5,000 State Grant"The Saratogian, 1991 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 54)
  - "Bike Path Unwanted in Interlaken Plan", Gazette reporter, 1990 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 55)
  - "Getting around in Suburbia", 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 56)
  - "Wilton Eyes Trial System", Gazette reporter, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 57)
  - "Wilton undertakes $1 million project to establish 50-mile trail system", 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 58)
  - "Bike Trials good for Community, Gazette reporter", 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 59)
  - "Malta considers options for Bike trail funding", 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 60)
  - "Town May Lose 180K Clifton Park Bike Trial", Gazette reporter, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 61)
  - "Bicycle organization picks Spa City for its National rally"The Saratogian, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 62)
  - "Municipalities seek Greenway grants for trails"Daily Gazette, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 63)
  - "Saratoga walking guide published"Daily Gazette, 1997 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 64)
  - "Saratogia bicyclist fair after mishap"Daily Gazette, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 65)
  - "Trails gets grants for extension"The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 66)
  - "No bike race in woods at Skidmore"The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 67)
  - "Skidmore bike trial to remain open to public"Daily Gazette, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 68)
  - "Biologists, bicyclists battle over Skidmore mountain bike trials", 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 69)
  - "Let hanging The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 70)
  - "Skidmore news: Cyclist may lose North woods privileges", 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 71)
  - "Residents get chance to name bikeway"Daily Gazette, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 72)
  - "Plans rolling along for bikeway"The Saratogian, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 73)
  - "Plans rolling along for bikeway"The Saratogian, folder 2, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 74)
  - "Let Sleeping Bike Paths Lie"The Ballston Journal, 1995 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 75)
  - "Bureaucratic wheels spin before panel Oks bike trail signs"Albany Times Union, 1995 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 76)
  - "Cermony opens heritage bike trials", 1994 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 77)
  - "Bevy of Urban Bikers Raises Safety Policing Challenges"The Christian Science Monitor, 1994 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 78)
  - "On the Trials", Poor Richard's Saratoga Journal, 1994 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 79)
  - "Push on for Spa City bike fail"The Saratogian, 1994 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 80)
  - "County bikeway gets approval for funding try"The Saratogian, 1994 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 81)
  - "NY awards $192K for 47 miles of bike paths in Saratoga", The Daily Gazette, 1994 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 82)
  - "City bike path gets Key grant from Feds"The Saratogian, 1994 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 83)
  - "ISTEA grant award makes front page headline"Troy Record, 1994 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 84)
  - "Land brought for trail system"The Saratogian, 1993 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 85)
  - "Colonie seeks $1 million for bike trial", 1993 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 86)
  - "Saratoga bike trial network may be three years away"The Ballston Journal, 1993 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 87)
  - "Go north with Greenway", Undated (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 88)
  - "Trial plan get boost from the panel"Albany Times Union, 1993 (Box 2 (4-Trails), Folder 89)